well thanks for having me guys you hear
me alright cool so I wanted to start by
just going over the Weebly story a
little bit telling you kind of how we
got to where we got to today and some of
the lessons we learned along the way so
what is Weebly first of all is if some
of you guys haven't heard of it
Weebly is a simple and powerful way to
create a site people want to create a
site they want to create a blog they
want to sell things online and they just
want to work they don't want any of the
frustrations around it so let me show
you a couple Weebly sites the first site
is a photographer from Toronto
showcasing their photography the second
site is an interior designer from Oregon
these they've actually been featured in
dwell magazine for their interior
designs run their website on Weebly the
third side is a graphic designer from
California can see all these sites just
look great
and not one line of HTML or CSS was
written for these sites this next site
is pretty special this is Brian he's 80
years old he retired and his passion is
building ukuleles and he started doing
his spare time went on Weebly and
created a website what do you know the
word got out and you know he could build
a couple ukuleles out of a shop per
month he now has a three to six month
back order of ukuleles and this last
site is really special to us
you may have seen that along with not
initiative I think last year but but
this group of students who had
volunteered in Kenya heard this story
about Omari that had been brutally
attacked while trying to fend his
orphanage and they didn't even have a
fence to defend themselves so they
created a Weebly website about this
posted it to Reddit and were able to
raise over $100,000 in less than a week
for the orphanage and they built a they
built a wall and a fence and much more
than that and that's actually now
helping out that orphanage in Kenya so a
little bit about our story and how we
got to where we are today in early 2006
as part of a class project at Penn State
we were came up with the same idea six
years ago we thought you know why is
this so hard why is it still so hard to
build a website we're seeing people all
around us that we're just struggling
and so we came up with the idea we start
working on now I'm gonna introduce you
to the theme in the presentation here
this is a graph of our new signups per
day now this is August 2006 this is real
data and you can see up at the top it's
six months after we started working on
Weebly so six months six months after we
wrote our first line of code our grand
sign of day we got 12 new users and you
know it's just kind of friends and
family it was so alpha stage this wasn't
something that was easy to pump out a
month is something that was difficult
that took some time to build so over
that summer dan and I and Chris were
working on it
here's October 2006 eight months later
so we've now been writing code and
working on the idea for eight months we
posted a private beta invitation on some
forums and we thought man this is gonna
blow up and we got about 30 people
signed up that day so you know around
this time I was up pretty late at night
was browsing / thought that kind of
tells you also you know that was the
most popular tech news site back then
and I was reading an article on Y
Combinator I said you know I think I've
heard about this coming before I'm not
really sure started reading the article
oh this sounds really cool it sounds
interesting
Oh application deadlines in two hours so
well I thought you know what the hell
I'll put something together really quick
you know it doesn't hurt to apply now I
didn't actually have enough time to call
a Dan or Chris to ask them if they'd be
willing to drop out of school moved to
San Francisco so I took a guess I
figured you know Chris would probably do
it he's a little he's a pretty wild guy
and Dan's a pretty wild guy too but but
I figured he might want to finish his
college career so you know we we applied
to YC with literally less than an hour
to go on the clock got accepted for an
interview drove up to Boston interviewed
we thought we thought it was great
incidentally the morning of the
interview I wake up check my phone I'm
ringing email bleary-eyed and and I got
an email from someone Congrats on the
tech crunching what the hell is this
about so open TechCrunch is just so
happened that TechCrunch operated by us
that morning the
you know I'm sure it definitely didn't
hurt with the interview but I also had
to explain this graph this is really
important this is not normally what a
tech crunching looks like normally it
goes straight up and straight back down
we had an invitation system in place you
know make sure our servers didn't crash
and so that's why I see it spread out
over more time but you know later that
night though you know Paul told us
expect a call from us by 7:00 p.m. the
same day we'll let you know if he made
it or not so you know we were pretty
nervous and we went out to dinner and we
sat down and literally I remember you
know 7:00 p.m. rolled around and 8:00
p.m. rolled around and we were all just
staring at our plates of food in front
of us like we literally couldn't eat we
were so nervous and then by 9:00 p.m.
we're like this is it we're definitely
not making it in they've called everyone
they've accepted and now they're just
calling the losers that aren't getting
in so I think around 9:00 9:30 the phone
call from Paul comes and I answer and
literally his first words were I'm
calling to end your college career so
you know funnily enough you know I ended
up talking to Dan later and say hey guys
you wanna do you wanna you know I know
we have a semester left but it sounds
crazy but how about we just drop out of
school moved to San Francisco what do
you think of it and Chris was like hell
yeah let's do it
and and as Dan I'm like Dan like what do
you think this is pretty crazy he's like
yeah I'm on board that sounds awesome so
you know this is this is a picture of us
that we took right after we got that
phone call I think this picture was also
right after we each took three shots at
the bar to celebrate and this is with
our friend Dana so the next graph is
January 2007 so we move out to San
Francisco start the Y Combinator program
it's now 11 months after we started
working on Weebly you know this is a
pretty long time this is almost a full
year after you started writing our first
line of code I want you to take a look
at this graph and I want you to notice
something
this isn't straight up into the right it
goes straight up it comes straight back
down now maybe you got a couple
squiggles here that a little that are a
little hopeful but things aren't looking
great we're getting less than a hundred
people per day signing up right now
almost a year after we started working
on Weebly
you know this is a picture of our first
office so we literally moved into an
apartment
we put three desks together you could
really tell how long ago this was
because that old-ass TV in the lower
right-hand corner and then and the
15-inch monitors and we literally just
pushed three desks together put it in
the living room and this is this is what
startup looks like we just worked our
asses off we had one important rule
which is we took Saturday off but
otherwise every other moment every other
waking moment was 24/7 work wasn't all
bad we had a great view of the San
Francisco Bay and you know this is this
is a fun story this is a little display
that Chris hacked up and he just put it
in the middle of the table and it showed
kind of some basic stats so it showed
like load average which you don't see
right here but it also showed total
users and logged in users and there's
three logging users here that's because
it was a three of us around the table
using Weebly and one of the one of our
biggest moments still I think in company
history was one night we were sitting
there and it went for you know and like
we were excited that was exciting so you
know in January 2007 we also got
featured on TechCrunch again this is
much more normal it goes straight up and
straight back down and you know again 11
months after we started working on
Weebly
this is April 2007 and there's a couple
hard times I also want to share cuz
sometimes you just hear about the good
stuff you don't hear about the bad stuff
you don't hear about the times were
really hard this is 14 months after you
start working on Whaley now the first
thing I want to address on this slide is
the signup graph I kind of want you to
look at the end there and notice you
know I think we were just oblivious and
very hopeful the time but that kind of
looks like it's heading down it's not
heading up it's actually heading in the
wrong direction at this point in April
2007 I mean we were just finishing the
YC program we were really hopeful that
we could raise money but you know
talking to some angel investors but at
one point we had less than 100 bucks in
our bank account and that's all the
money we had we you know we spent money
on two things early on we spent money on
rent and we spent money at the bar
and and and that's pretty much it and
you know we were pretty hopeful but rent
was coming up in two weeks and we had to
pay rent in two weeks so we started
talking about raising a friends and
family around we started talking about
moving to San Jose to save 800 bucks a
month and rent and luckily we didn't do
that yeah and you know luckily sort of
right in the nick of time
we end up raising 650k angel round from
from Ron from Steve Anderson Mike maples
a bunch of angels this is another thing
that really dates this story that big
stack of paperwork is when equity
financing looks like these days you know
all the financing most really stage
finances are done via convertible note
to three pages tops this is a fat stack
for an equity financing so you know the
next big thing for us was being featured
in Newsweek now this used to be of a
really big deal I don't know today if
it's as much of a big deal but back then
this was a huge deal this was the thing
that your parents like bought 10 copies
the magazine afford it to everyone they
knew and so this was a really big deal
15 months in that that was definitely a
high point and that's what that looks
like so now you're seeing the effect of
what being featured in Newsweek looks
like you know again it's a very similar
pattern it goes up and it comes right
back down you're now noticing you know
it settles higher that's definitely a
good sign but it's still going down it's
not going up this is 15 months after we
started working on Weebly you know
here's a shot of our office here in in
July 2007 and it's that's Dan sitting
there and that's also our stats
dashboard that you could kind of see
what's going on next big moment for us
around the same time was being featured
in time so we're featuring time is one
of the 50 best websites of 2007 this is
18 months after you start working on
Weebly a year and a half after we
started working on Weebly and things
still aren't taking off there's no
hockey stick here things are actually
going in the wrong direction now I want
to try something out here raise your
hand if you're currently working on a
startup
okay now keep
hand up nope nope cute keep your hands
up now keep your hand up only if you've
been working on for over 18 months okay
right that's what I thought it's a long
time this is a really long time and we
didn't have any we didn't have too much
positive we were just sort of naive we
were naively hopeful that things were
working out and we knew it was a good
problem to be solving we're getting
feedback from our users but you know the
metrics weren't entirely there yet and
this is where it changes this is this is
20 months and finally finally 20 months
after we start working on we were seeing
our first real traction now this is good
this is where your your rate of
acquiring news per day is increasing
linearly that's a pretty good thing and
one thing to notice you know you you
might think hey if only I get on
TechCrunch I'll blow up you know my
company will be successful if I just get
on TechCrunch well look all the way back
there just via word-of-mouth now we are
now getting more users every single day
than if we were featured in newsweek
time or TechCrunch in july 2008 we moved
in our first rail office 29 months after
you start working on we leave funny
story that TV on the wall got stolen our
office got broken into the first week we
moved in that was fun
getting a call from the police officer
at the next day bein like you gotta come
deal with your office is busted so you
know here's another picture and this is
this was just it was small it was 1400
square feet we ended up fitting I think
about 12 people there and and you know
around the summer time we started
looking at our bank account balance and
and you know we're like okay well you
know how much runway do we have this is
an important thing to know if you're not
profitable how much runway do we have we
said okay well well we really need to
start raising money in September
you know maybe October in November we're
gonna run out of money it's you know so
so we said well what the hell let's
let's give it a shot at least start
making some money so July 2008 when we
choose Weebly Pro we also sell domain
names now and when we start at that time
and you know things were looking good
but if you know anything about the fall
of 2008 it was just a really bad time to
be raising money so we went out there
and you know might have worked but
the terms were just not what we are
looking for so this is a graph of our
company bank account balance I actually
hacked up Vanguard's graphic you know
like flash graph to plot an XML feed to
graph this for you guys this is 34
months after we started working on
Weebly and it was pretty low and and and
this is you know this is this is another
hard time we basically we we looked at
our bank account balance and we said
okay well you know revenue is increasing
and things are going in the right
direction then we're pretty hopeful we
could squeeze through but you know but
we can't pay our bills next month so
we're we gonna do about it so you know
obviously payroll was just never an
option we're obviously gonna pay payroll
if we had to cut our own salaries that
was gonna be one thing but for people
with employed that was just not an
option not to pay that so the next step
was to get out of calendar literally I
remember getting out a big calendar on a
piece of paper and mapping out all our
bills on which days they were due and
how much money we thought we were gonna
make in the meantime to just barely
squeaked by and and then there was
really two types of bills that we
labeled there was one there was a type
of bill that if you didn't pay it you
got a late fee and the second type of
bill if you didn't pay it they shot your
servers off so obviously we had to pay
that second category but you know in
January 2009 which is which is a great
month for us you know we finally hit
break-even now this is where things
started turning in the in the profitable
direction and you know this is where you
first start seeing a working business
model it finally clicks and you can see
a little bit of history out there 35
months that's three years after we
started working on it we finally hit a
working business model this is February
2010 and now things are looking great
now we're off to the races this is four
years after we started working on Weebly
and I want you to notice all the way in
the back that that Newsweek that time
you know the TechCrunch articles they're
just blips on the radar you know now
every day we're getting about 5,000 new
users per day all of the award math it's
all organic growth in March 2011
sixty-one months after we started we
partnered with Sequoia Capital we love
them as partners and brought them on
board to help grow the business
and that brings us to today so where are
we now
today we bleep our is about 2% of the
active web sites on the internet that's
all based on public data from net craft
every month 15% of the United States
visits a Weebly website and my favorite
stat here is our Net Promoter Score our
Net Promoter Score is over 80% now if
you're not familiar with what a net
promoter score is that's you know that
means 88% of people who answered this
survey said 9 or 10 likely they're gonna
recommend we do a friend as a point of
comparison I think apples is 67% that's
considered excellent this explains
everything about our business a quick
tour of the office here moved in this
office about a year ago this is what it
looks like when you walk in this is this
a quick snapshot of our lobby and
conference room at the front here's our
open work plan area and you know we
really like this because you could
really talk and communicate but
obviously it gets noisy so one of the
things that we give everyone who works
at Weebly as bose noise-canceling
headphones to block out the noise it's a
TV room great for catching a big game
especially the Giants games have been on
lately and this is this is our kind of
you know kitchen slash rec area
downstairs we get super competitive on
ping-pong pool foosball one thing I want
you to notice is that bookshelf in the
back actually if you go up to that and
you know the right book to pull it
actually opens up I'm not sure how well
you can see that but it's it's its
policy we can't show anyone pictures of
inside the secret room unless you come
visit so we'd love to have you over to
check that out
so you know just for shits and giggles I
pulled our bank account balance from
this morning that's what our company
thank you balance looks like now and
this is 80 months after we started
working on Weebly I think the important
message here is it's still an unfinished
story you know I mean as large as we've
been able to grow this is just the
beginning so you know what's next for
Weebly well six years ago we thought the
same thing you know making a site it's
just hard you know and today people are
just as frustrated you know just as
confused and all they really want to do
is participate in the Internet and you
know what most people can't participate
in the internet the way they'd like to
you know people just want to you know
showcase their business showcase their
art or their talents and sell things
online and it's still too difficult for
them so you know as much as we've done
the last six years we think we've just
built a foundation and what's most
exciting is is what we're building it
right now and there's just a whole lot
of work left to do so I think the number
one takeaway of everything is you can't
succeed if you quit too often I've seen
people that build something for six
months and then they launch it and then
two months later they stop working on it
like how do you expect that to work you
know behind every I think we've seen
today behind every quote-unquote
overnight success you see people who
have been working for years and years
and years and if you want to build a
truly big and meaningful company it's
gonna take you seven to ten years of
your life you know don't give up so
easily you just gotta keep going
even at the early days for everyone
including us it didn't look great you
just have to push through and know that
you're working on a valuable problem and
keep pushing through so lastly I'll
close with it you know if you'd like to
help us finish the story that that's
still in progress we'd love to talk to
you but I won't go into much about that
if you have any other questions please
email me hope to see you at the party
tonight and thank you very much